<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Git | Andreas Kleiber]]></title>
  <link href="http://andreaskleiber.de/blog/categories/git/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andreaskleiber.de/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-04T14:40:25+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://andreaskleiber.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andreas Kleiber]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Youtrack GitHub Integration]]></title>
    <link href="http://andreaskleiber.de/blog/2016/02/04/youtrack-github-integration/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-04T13:42:40+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://andreaskleiber.de/blog/2016/02/04/youtrack-github-integration</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>The challenge</h2>

<p>You can link your YouTrack projects to GitHub projects. When you have setup the VCS integration successful you can edit Youtrack issues via GIT commits.
When I tried it some time ago with my personal account it just worked out of the box. But when I started using an organization account things stopped working. After overcoming all obstacles I got it working. My frustration level reached a maximum when I tried to monitor only the master branch. It just again did not work as described in JetBrains documentation.
I am so glad YouTrack&rsquo;s support team is fast as hell, as far as I can tell.</p>

<p>So in order to make your life easier I will show you the neccessary steps to setup GitHub integration in YouTrack using an organization account and monitoring specific branches.</p>

<h2>The way</h2>

<p>We assume you have setup YouTrack and GitHub accounts.</p>

<h3>Setup VCS integration in your YouTrack Project</h3>

<p><img src="../images/2016-02-04-youtrack-github-integration/vcs-setup.webp" title="YouTrack VCS setup" ></p>

<ol>
<li>Navigate to your YouTrack project <code>project - edit project - VCS</code></li>
<li>Add a new GitHub VCS integration</li>
<li>Create an auth token (just press the link)</li>
<li>Repository owner = your organization account name</li>
</ol>


<p><img src="../images/2016-02-04-youtrack-github-integration/branch-setup.webp" title="YouTrack VCS branch settings" ></p>

<ol>
<li>Choose the desired repository</li>
<li>To only log commits from the master, use <code>+:refs/heads/(master)</code> for &ldquo;Monitor Branches&rdquo;</li>
<li>When you are finished, YouTrack changes the VCS Login from your organization&rsquo;s name to the account name that owns the OAuth token</li>
</ol>


<h3>Edit YouTrack issues via GIT commits</h3>

<p>You can put every command that you can use via the YouTrack command dialog (ctrl + option + J on OSX) in your GIT commits.
Just make sure your commit email matches your YouTrack account email.</p>

<p><img src="../images/2016-02-04-youtrack-github-integration/issue.webp" title="YouTrack VCS issue" >
<img src="../images/2016-02-04-youtrack-github-integration/commit.webp" title="YouTrack VCS commit" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
